vinnies.org.au 2013-12-03

# Privacy - St Vincent de Paul Society - Good Works

###  **Online Privacy Policy**

The St Vincent de Paul Society of Australia (the “Society”) is committed to protecting your privacy in accordance with the National Privacy Principles.  Consistent with the Privacy Act 1988 as amended by the Privacy Amendment (Private Sector) Act 2000 (the Act), the Society endorses fair information handling practices. Any information provided, including identification of individuals, will be used only for the purpose for which it has been collected.

Personal information is confidential and is not passed on to any other agency without your permission.

Statistical information is shared with other departments and agencies. An example of this would be reporting to government agencies regarding the number of people accessing our homeless or aged care facilities.

If you wish to access the information we hold about you or have any questions about this please contact the Society’s head office in your State.

Information that has been collected will be amended if you consider details are incorrect.

Any personal information that is considered to be beyond its "use by" date will be destroyed.

Reasonable steps will be taken to ensure that any personal information collected will be held secure and only accessible by appointed "key" holders.

###    
**Email Addresses**

Email addresses provided via the website will be used to respond to specific user queries and will only be added to our information mailing list if your permission is given. Your email address will not be disclosed to any other party without your knowledge and consent and as intended, unless required by law.  
When you visit the website, our Internet Service Provider’s (ISP) computer server, logs the following information which is provided by your browser for statistical purposes only:

  * the type of browser and operating system you are using;
  * your top level domain name (for example .com, .org, .au, .uk etc);
  * the address of the referring website (for example, the previous website that you visited);
  * your server's IP address (a number which is unique to the machine through which you are
  * connected to the Internet: usually one of your service provider's machines).
  * In addition, the server logs the following information:
  * the date and time of your visit; and
  * the address of the pages accessed and the documents downloaded.

All of this information the Society uses only for statistical analysis or systems administration purposes. No attempt will be made to identify users or their browsing activities, except in the unlikely event of an investigation where a law enforcement agency may exercise a warrant.

Please note that in an effort to promote the St Vincent de Paul Society and its good works, the Society does at times purchase contact lists from data companies which comply with the National Privacy Act and ADMA standards. The St Vincent de Paul Society adheres to the National Privacy Act.

###  **Subscriptions**

Some pages of this website provide the facility for users to subscribe to email mailing lists. To subscribe to these services users must provide a valid email address. These email addresses will only be used for the purpose for which you have provided it and you will not be added to any other mailing lists unless you specifically request that this be done.  
Your email address will not be disclosed without your consent.  
Links to other websites  
This website contains links to other websites. The Society is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites.  
Our privacy policy covers the privacy practices for the website, but does not extend to links to other websites. When you leave the website (http://www.vinnies.org.au) or the state pages of this website, you will be going to websites that are beyond our control. These other websites may send their own cookies to users, collect data, or solicit personal information.

###  **Contact details**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this website, or your dealings with this website, you can contact the Society’s office in your State.
